# ETL, Data Modeling, Data Quality, Data Science & Data Visualization

# TianShuai Tristan Lu

1-226-998-1850 | tristan.lu.uo@gmail.com

Data Analyst with 6 years of experience in data science, data ETL, data visualization and Web UI, Tristan has been heavily engaged in BI & AI processing of data using Python, SQL and Power BI for banking & retail businesses. With true passion in technology and business, Vincent has been proven to be high performed and accountable team player in various projects.

#### **CORE COMPETENCIES**

- ✓ Banking Business Process
- ✓ Business Requirement Collection
- ✓ Dashboard & Reporting
- ✓ Client Facing

- ✓ ETL, Automation, Data Pipeline
- ✓ Data Science
- ✓ DevOps Development
- ✓ Agile Methodology

## TECHNICAL BACKGROUND

- Design & Development: Web Application UI, Data engineering, Data ETL, Model and automation design
- Software: Azure SQL DB, OpenShift, Databricks, ADF, Power BI, Tableau, Jira, ServiceNow, Autosys, draw.io
- **Programming**: Python, TSQL, Stored Procedure, VBA, Unix Script, Java, Pyspark, Docker, Jenkins, Github, HTML5, JavaScript, React.js, Angular.js, AWS Elastic Beanstalk service & EC2 instance, S3 bucket, SSIS, SSAS

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## Data Analyst Co-op | RBC Royal Bank of Canada, Toronto

May 2021 - Dec 2021

- Re-designed the **Web UI**, Data updates and **ETL** process of **RBC Cost Redistribution Platform** to better allocate **RBC property/transit costs** in terms of space management, financial calculation and payment allocation
- Corporate Real Estate Information Database investigation and housekeeping base on source identification, naming convention, last update time and usage analyses
- Created Workforce Management Portal for managers maintaining employee vaccination status in FutureWork database which provides information to VPs for company's work mode decision making
- Developed & integrated an Enterprise Application Portfolios Management Dashboard in RBC IIPM system to provide an overall picture of IT Management and Governance for higher management's decision making
- Containerized in-house web applications with CI/CD development and process using Jenkins and Introduced automated way to deploy applications to Enterprise OpenShift Cloud Platform across environments
- Developed Global EDI Data Exchange Framework between SAP SAF and Vendor-Endpoints of RBC through REST API, SFTP, including format conversion from iDoc to CSV, Naming Convention and Orchestration for 30 workflows, which covers procurement, employee, invoicing data etc

## Digital Market Analyst | Trip.com Group, China

Jun 2018 – Sep 2018

- Developed an online analytical plugin on monitoring travel products using Python, increased certain product sales by 15% through KPI analysis, such as product clicks, customer viewing time
- Designed A/B testing to monitor and record the KPIs, such as time-on-page, click-through rate and conversion rate
- Consolidated website performance tagging structure, created analytical requirement documents for travel products
- Conducted conversion latency analysis and created **latency projection model** which provided key insights to the customer value calculation and attribution.
- Created sustainable automated solution for **report scheduling** and **delivery** to ensure **cross-department reference**.
- Automated project procedure in Python and VBA and save 90% time consumed.

#### ACADEMIC PROJECTS

•	P1 – Azure Databricks for banking data analysis & Transformation	Jul 2020 – Aug 2020
•	P2 – AWS Daily Exchange Trading Data ETL Pipeline & Reporting using python framework	Sep 2020 - Oct 2020
•	P3 – AWS Image Resizing App	Apr 2020 – May 2020
•	P4 – BI Solution End to End Implementation for re-seller DM and Dashboard Delivery	Mar 2020 – Apr 2020
•	P5 – Facial Key-Point Recognition & Emotion Detection using Neutral Network Model	Nov 2019 – Dec 2019
•	P6 – Shopify style of Music Review Website Design and Development	Oct 2019 – Nov 2019
	-	

## **EDUCATION**

Master of Engineering, Electrical & Computer Engineering   University of Ottawa	Sep 2020 – Jun 2022
Master of Engineering, Software Engineering   Western University, Toronto	Sep 2019 – Oct 2020
Bachelor, Computer Engineering   Shandong University of Finance & Economics, China	Sep 2015 – Jun 2019